<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Agile on Dmitry M - Veridis Quo</title>
    <link>https://dmitrym0.github.io/tags/agile/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Agile on Dmitry M - Veridis Quo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dmitrym0.github.io/tags/agile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Personal Agile: Iteration 5 (COVID-19 edition)</title>
      <link>https://dmitrym0.github.io/posts/personal-agile-iteration-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmitrym0.github.io/posts/personal-agile-iteration-5/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been pretty hard to focus on anything other than what&amp;rsquo;s going on in the world the last two weeks. I didn&amp;rsquo;t really successfully complete the iteration. We&amp;rsquo;ve been sent home from work about a week ago which freed up a lot of time that&amp;rsquo;s been allocated to the commute. Theoretically. Unfortunately focus has been hard to come by.
The only take away I have from this iteration is that I&amp;rsquo;ve significantly reversed my position on UI/UX.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Agile: Iteration 4</title>
      <link>https://dmitrym0.github.io/posts/personal-agile-iteration-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmitrym0.github.io/posts/personal-agile-iteration-4/</guid>
      <description>Interesting iteration. Overall agile approach has been a net positive. I likely would&amp;rsquo;ve have been approximately as successful, but deliberate approach to planning and reviews yields interesting artifacts (of which this blog post is one) and provides for an interesting trajectory overview.
I made good progress on my tasks this iteration:
adding two additional chapters reviewed to &amp;ldquo;First 90 days&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s becoming a bit tedious, but I feel it&amp;rsquo;s critical to finish this book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Agile: Iteration 2</title>
      <link>https://dmitrym0.github.io/posts/personal-agile-iteration-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmitrym0.github.io/posts/personal-agile-iteration-2/</guid>
      <description>The goal for this iteration was to:
work on my little SwiftUI app finish reading a book (&amp;ldquo;The first 90 days&amp;rdquo;) maintain my fitness habits Conclusions Overall the iteration went well. In the screenshot above, you can tell that I wildly underestimated how much time summarizing the current book would take: I estimated an hour, but it ended up being 3 times as much (3 hours).
Then, I spent way too much on my app, 10 pomodoros (roughly 5 hours) vs 3 hours initially estimated.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
