<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on Dmitry M - Veridis Quo</title>
    <link>https://dmitrym0.github.io/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on Dmitry M - Veridis Quo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dmitrym0.github.io/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ncdu - ncurses disk usage</title>
      <link>https://dmitrym0.github.io/posts/ncdu-ncurses-disk-usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmitrym0.github.io/posts/ncdu-ncurses-disk-usage/</guid>
      <description>At some point harddrive space was cheap, but with the advent of SSDs and cheap “Cloud VMs” that is no longer the case. For example, the cheapest VM on VULTR is $5/month and has a 15 gig SSD drive. It&amp;rsquo;s suddenly very important to maximize drive usage again. This is where ncdu comes in. It displays a nice ncurses interface that visualizes the usage breakdown.
So useful key bindings:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RAID5: Recovering from 2-drive failure during rebuild</title>
      <link>https://dmitrym0.github.io/posts/raid5-multiple-disk-recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmitrym0.github.io/posts/raid5-multiple-disk-recovery/</guid>
      <description>RAID is amazing technology. It lets us take a bunch of cheap disks an arrange them in various configurations that present these disks as one large disk. A particularly popular type of RAID for home users is RAID5. A RAID5 array is typically comprised of 3 disks, however only 2&amp;frasl;3 of the disk space is available since 1&amp;frasl;3 of the space is used for recovery purposes if one of the disks fail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tircd, irc twitter gateway</title>
      <link>https://dmitrym0.github.io/posts/tircd-twitter-gateway/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmitrym0.github.io/posts/tircd-twitter-gateway/</guid>
      <description>I published my tircd branch. If you&amp;rsquo;re unfamiliar with tircd it&amp;rsquo;s a daemon that presents Twitter as an IRC channel. I merged this really old branch that implements Twitter lists as channels with the semi official google code mirror branch. I created a pull request but it hasn&amp;rsquo;t been acted on yet.
I consume my instant messaging via IRC (with the help of minbif) and now Twitter too. Quite convenient.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>