<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Emacs on Dmitry M - Veridis Quo</title>
    <link>https://dmitrym.online/tags/emacs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Emacs on Dmitry M - Veridis Quo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dmitrym.online/tags/emacs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Achievement Unlocked: Open Source Contribution</title>
      <link>https://dmitrym.online/posts/open-source-contribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmitrym.online/posts/open-source-contribution/</guid>
      <description>I did it. My Emacs package, org-hyperscheduler, is now live on MELPA, here.
I&amp;rsquo;m overjoyed. It&amp;rsquo;s a big deal for me, because I&amp;rsquo;ve been a long time beneficiary of open source software and I&amp;rsquo;m glad to finally be able to give back. It&amp;rsquo;s the first piece of software that I started out writing for myself and got to a state where it&amp;rsquo;s useable for other folks.
Once version 1 was stable, I submitted a pull request to MELPA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journaling prompts in Emacs</title>
      <link>https://dmitrym.online/posts/journaling-prompts-with-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmitrym.online/posts/journaling-prompts-with-emacs/</guid>
      <description>One of my daily rituals is journaling. It&amp;rsquo;s been shown to have positive impact on quality of life (citation needed). I find it helps me decompress but it&amp;rsquo;s also a permanent record of my thoughts and my life&amp;rsquo;s minutiae.
I usually set a timer for 5 minutes and go to town. One particular challenge I have, is that some times I don&amp;rsquo;t really know what to write about. Recently I came upon the idea of journaling prompts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is hyper-scheduling?</title>
      <link>https://dmitrym.online/posts/what-is-hyperscheduling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmitrym.online/posts/what-is-hyperscheduling/</guid>
      <description>Hyperscheduling?; TLDR Hyperscheduling is the idea of fully planning your day using a calendar. Every minute of the day is assigned to some task using a calendar.
Hyperscheduling in more detail Hyperscheduling is only part of a productivity system. It helps me plan my day:
Select a set of tasks for today (this is done outside of hyperscheduling, using GTD or another system). Prioritize your tasks in order of importance. Lay your tasks out on the calendar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note taking and discovery</title>
      <link>https://dmitrym.online/posts/note-taking-and-discovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmitrym.online/posts/note-taking-and-discovery/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been taking notes consistently, probably starting in university. The challenge for me was never capture but retrieval. I suspect that&amp;rsquo;s true for most people.
The interesting thing about zettelcasten is how Luhramn optimized his sytem for retrieval. Related subjects were proximate, he used a linking system of sorts that allowed his cards to be filed under number of different topics.
In digital note taking, proximity is difficult to simulate. Hyperlinking is the first step of course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Omnifocus style reviews with org-mode</title>
      <link>https://dmitrym.online/posts/omnifocus-review-with-org-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dmitrym.online/posts/omnifocus-review-with-org-mode/</guid>
      <description>I started using Emacs and org-mode in earnest in the middle of 2019. At that point in time I was using Omnifocus to track my tasks and Bearapp for notes. I was missing plaintext functionality. Since then I&amp;rsquo;ve reproduced most of the functionality that Omnifocus offerred except one particular feature: reviews.
In GTD, reviews occupy a pretty important niche. Without regular task and project reviews task lists tend to grow out of control and become polutted.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
